Hi my name is Lauren and I'm here to discuss how to make an afro with straight hair.
For your temporary afro in order to go with an outfit it is easier if your hair is basically short to medium length.
Once your hair is a little bit longer it makes it a little bit more difficult to get the actual afro style.
If your hair is longer one thing that you can do in order to help you achieve that style is you can actually take your hair in sections and clip them up in order to shorten the length of your hair so if I bring this up, if I just kind of clip this.
Now what you want to do is an X using two bobby pins in order to clip their hair up.
The X will help secure the hair up there so that way you can get started.
After you have put your hair up or if your hair is shorter you don't need to go through with this step.
You are going to take a small curling iron.
You want a small barrel because afros tend to have a very tight tight curl and you are going to curl very tiny sections at a time all throughout the entire head.
After you have curled those sections, I have already curled a few here on the top, you are going to use a comb and actually back comb the hair up.
Back combing is done in a three step process, I am turning this that way so that you may see.
You are going to take your comb and you are going to hold it about mid shaft.
You are going to go down three times, one, two three, one, two, three, one, two, three.
That way you start to get a little bit more of matted hair which will hold your style up.
Now since we are doing an afro you would want to do a good amount of that hair where so that way it will stand up the way that an afro would.
So you are going to continue teasing those sections kind of matting them so that way you have more of an afro look.
As you see if I am working up the hair shaft how it kind of begins to form more of your afro look.
Once you curl everything you are going to smooth it a little bit but you don't want to smooth it too much because then you are going to fall, spray it, and then if you need to at any given point you may want to go over and reinforce that bit of a tighter curl.
If you work around with this method throughout your entire head you will get more of what the afro look is.
Again if your hair is longer you are going to want to pin it up in order to make your job a little easier and that is how to get an afro with straight hair.